### Robert Hostetler

Office 365 Architect and Web Developer

hello@roberthostetler.org

## Summary

Experience in designing, building, integrating, implementing, delivering, operating, and managing highly available and resilient IT Infrastructures, in particular HTML and ASP.NET websites, SharePoint, SQL Server Databases, and related/supporting services.

My twelve years of experience in IT is a great foundation to execute business objectives. Working in the IT areas of Conduent, Nike, Parkview Health, the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and Xerox I gained experience that gives you the versatility to place me in different contexts with confidence that I can achieve the level of excellence an organization expects.

I have been successful at communicating and influencing with individuals of all capacities, including at the senior management level, through following the best practices of the Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC). I am eager to gain greater insights into the business by collaborating with an experienced team.

My passions involve supporting the arts, volunteering, working with people who value teamwork and being an active citizen in my community.

# Experience

Atos ITO - SharePoint Architect at Atos October 2014 - Present

Provide Information Technology Outsourcing (ITO) solutions to Fortune 500 scale clients who need solution architecture, proactive maintenance, configuration, patching, and incident identification and resolution for their SharePoint On-Premises or Online (as part of Office 365) environments. Designs environments for optimal use and performance based on client's requirements. Plan out the entire environment from server and network layout to how services are going to be load balanced.

Note: Initial employment with Xerox's ITO business and transitioned to Atos in June 2015 after the acquisition was completed.

Atos ITO - Supporting Conduent at Conduent January 2017 - Present

Supported Conduent for staff augmentation of their IT Infrastructure Architecture team accountable for: SharePoint, OneDrive, Search, Yammer, and the overarching Office 365 Tenant cross workload integration with a total user population of 96,000.

- ♦ Involved with scoping of 23 post transition and calendar year 2018 projects for Office 365 and SharePoint.
- ♦ Involved with migration of content from other Office 365 Tenants to Conduent's Tenant.
- ♦ Testing of functionality that has not yet been enabled for all users of the Conduent Tenant.

#### Atos ITO - Supporting Xerox at Xerox

May 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Supported Xerox for staff augmentation of their IT Infrastructure Architecture team (4-5 total members) covering Xerox's internal corporate SharePoint, File and Shared Workgroup, DocuShare, Search, and Yammer hosting services with a total population of 143,000+.

- ♦ Contributed toward migration of services to Office 365 for Xerox and Conduent supporting the corporate separation. Services covered include: SharePoint Team Sites, SharePoint Personal Sites, Personal File Shares, Workgroup File Shares, DocuShare Collections, Enterprise Search, and Yammer. The areas I focused on were Enterprise Search and Yammer
- ♦ Responsible for planning, coordination, and execution of the transition of Yammer authentication from Yammer SSO for to Office 365 identities for the Xerox Tenant.
- ♦ Utilized provided standardized project management document templates: Solution Proposal, Solution Design, and Charter.
- ♦ Responsible for the evaluation and report production evaluating the use of existing CA Site Minder based single sign-on services replacing existing NTLM and Kerberos based authentication for SharePoint 2010 based services.

# Xerox ITO - Supporting NIKE, Inc. at Nike

October 2014 - April 2015 (7 months)

Supported NIKE, Inc. as a local liaison between Nike's World Headquarters (WHQ) campus in Beaverton, Oregon and the Xerox/Atos globally distributed SharePoint Architecture and Support team that was contractually responsible for Nike's On-Premises SharePoint farms.

- ♦ Worked from multiple locations: Usually at the data center that contained the WHQ SharePoint farm, Nike's WHQ campus when face to face meetings were requested, and remotely during off-hours meetings with those in other time zones and high severity support occurrences.
- ♦ Configuring and administering multi-server, enterprise-class SharePoint On-Premises farms to ensure day-to-day running. Take care of patching, ensuring uptime, monitoring and tuning performance, and server maintenance.
- ♦ Performed under deadline as member of a quick-response team that are farm admins and server admins, with the access required via Microsoft Remote Desktop to make any needed changes to the Nike SharePoint farms. Used written SOAP Notes to clearly document the status for anyone else involved in resolving an issue. S = Subjective (client's observation of issue), O = Objective (symptoms that can be measured), A = Assessment (diagnosis of the issue), P = Plan (what the next steps are).
- ♦ Gathered best practices on meeting SLA expectations from the team responsible for monitoring compliance followed by cross training and monitoring teammates on following them to help ensure that they were consistently met. SLA fines could be as high as \$200,000 per violation, so this was helpful with keeping the team profitable.
- ♦ Led daily hand off meeting between the first and second shifts so the next shift would be better prepared for their work day and to help ensure the SLAs attached to the SharePoint environment were met.
- ◆ Preparation of technical documentation.

# ASP.NET and SharePoint Designer, Developer, and Administrator at Parkview Health November 2006 - March 2014 (7 years 5 months)

Member of team responsible for HTML, ASP.NET, and SharePoint based solutions.

♦ Technical lead on the implementation of the SharePoint 2007 iterations of parkview.com (general information about the organization), parkviewtotalhealth.com (information regarding the Signature Care PPO network, Occupational Health, Employee Assistance, and Workplace Wellness service lines), and the corporate extranet. Technical lead on the implementation of the SharePoint 2010 iteration of the Community Connect Extranet. Collaborated with a team of developers, designers, and project managers on utilizing the software development lifecycle to assist with improving productivity and quality.

- ♦ Utilized the following tools regarding managing SharePoint: STSADM command-line tool, IIS, and Central Administration for the overall SharePoint environment. SQL Server for creating custom reports. SharePoint Designer for custom workflows. InfoPath for custom forms. Citrix Receiver, Microsoft Remote Desktop, VMware vSphere, VPN, and Dell vWorkspace for remote access.
- ♦ Designed, developed, implemented, and supported custom web applications with ASP.NET and either a SQL Server or Oracle database. These types of applications were used when the requirements made the following a priority: speed, stability, smaller footprint, greater flexibility with designing the user interface, supporting a wider variety of devices, and unique and custom functionality.
- ♦ Coordinated with Executive Assistants, Parkview Health leadership, an Active Directory Administrator, and a Citrix XenApp Administrator on the creation of a Board of Directors portal.
- ♦ Utilized the Waterfall model of the Software Development Lifecycle for being stewards of the systems that we maintained. Was involved in all of the phases: requirements analysis, software design, implementation, testing, integration, deployment, and maintenance.
- ♦ Provided training, guides, and support to co-workers on items in my department's service catalog.

# Front-end Web Developer and Content Analyst

February 2006 - November 2006 (10 months)

Member of the Information Technology Outsourcing services team located in the Washington, D.C. area to specifically work with U.S. Government clients.

♦ Also Designed and developed branding materials including logos, color schemes, templates for Microsoft Office, and business cards; designed brochures and a display to use with Job Fairs and Trade shows using Photoshop and Illustrator for Drayton, Drayton & Lamar, Inc.

# DDL - Supporting the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development at U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development

February 2006 - November 2006 (10 months)

- ♦ Operated as a contractor provided by Drayton, Drayton & Lamar, Inc. (DDL) for the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development. Required to successfully pass a U.S. Government background investigation (via Standard Form 85P, Questionnaire for Public Trust Positions)
- ♦ Performed under deadline as member of a quick-response content team with the access required to make any content changes in the environment which may be needed.

♦ Retouched photographs and graphics, designed and developed animations, and updated content for their Office of Public Affairs Internet (hud.gov) and Intranet sites.

### Education

Purdue University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Graphics Technology, 1998 - 2003